Guide to the Duke Family papers on the Duke Farms residence, 1859-2004 and undated RL.01437
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Architectural Records, 1897-1992 and undated
  - Duke Farms Proposed Mansion, 1907-1916, 1938 and undated
    - Proposed Country House for Mr. J.B. Duke, Basement Floor Plan. Horace Trumbauer, architect. 1909 Jul. Blueprint, photocopy. (Oversize-folder C1D3F1)
    - Proposed Country House for Mr. J.B. Duke, Basement Plan. Horace Trumbauer, architect. [1909 Apr 9]. Blueprint, photocopy. (Oversize-folder C1D3F1)
    - Proposed Country House for Mr. J.B. Duke, Sub-Basement Floor Plan. Horace Trumbauer, architect. 1909 Jul. Blueprint, photocopy. (Oversize-folder C1D3F1)
    - Proposed Country House for Mr. J.B. Duke, Plan Below Sub-Basement, Section Taken 6'0" Below Sub-Basement Floor. Horace Trumbauer, architect. 1909 Sep 14. Blueprint, photocopy. (Oversize-folder C1D3F1)
    - Proposed Country House for Mr. J.B. Duke, Longitudinal Section. Horace Trumbauer, architect. [1909]. Blueprint, photocopy. (Oversize-folder C1D3F1)
    - Proposed Country House for Mr. J.B. Duke, Cross Section, Longitudinal Section. Horace Trumbauer, architect. 1909 Sep 14. Blueprint, photocopy. (Oversize-folder C1D3F1)
    - Proposed Country House for Mr. J.B. Duke, Transverse Section. Horace Trumbauer, architect. 1909 Jul. Blueprint, photocopy. (Oversize-folder C1D3F1)
    - Proposed Country House for Mr. J.B. Duke, First Floor Plan. Horace Trumbauer, architect. [1909]. Ink on linen paper, photocopy. (Oversize-folder C1D3F1)
    - Proposed Country House for Mr. J.B. Duke, Second Floor Plan. Horace Trumbauer, architect. [1909]. Ink on linen paper, photocopy. (Oversize-folder C1D3F1)
    - Proposed Country House for Mr. J.B. Duke, Plan of Foundation Area "Duke Farms" Somerville, N.J. Nelson & Baldwin. 1938 Dec 13. Blueprint, photocopy. (Oversize-folder C1D3F1)
    - Proposed Country House for Mr. J.B. Duke, Sub-Basement Floor Plan, Foundation Plan. Donald H. Stires Associates. 1961 Oct. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D3F1)
    - Sketch 4, Elevation of Bank Wall. undated. Pencil. (Oversize-folder C1D3F2)
    - Sketch 4: [Slope of Great Lawn]. undated. Pen. (Oversize-folder C1D3F2)
    - Section Showing Terrace as a Lawn. undated. Pencil, ink andwatercolor. (Oversize-folder C1D3F2)
    - [Sketch: Slope of Great Lawn]. undated. Pencil, ink and watercolor. (Oversize-folder C1D3F2)
    - [Sketch: Slope of Great Lawn]. undated. Pencil, ink and watercolor. (Oversize-folder C1D3F2)
    - [Sketch: Slope of Great Lawn]. undated. Pencil, ink and watercolor. (Oversize-folder C1D3F2)
    - Design 1. Horace Trumbauer, architect. undated. Pencil, ink and watercolor (green monotone). (Oversize-folder C1D3F2)
    - Design 1. Horace Trumbauer, architect. undated. Pencil and ink. (Oversize-folder C1D3F2)
    - Design 2. Horace Trumbauer, architect. undated. Pencil, ink and watercolor (green monotone). (Oversize-folder C1D3F2)
    - [Proposed Front Elevation]. Horace Trumbauer, architect. [1909]. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D3F2)
    - [Proposed Front Elevation]. Horace Trumbauer, architect. [1909]. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D3F2)
    - Proposed Country House for J.B. Duke, Esq at Somerville, NJ, First Floor. Kendall, Taylor & Stevens, architects. [circa 1907]. Pencil and auburn watercolor. (Oversize-folder C1D3F3)
    - Proposed Country House for J.B. Duke, Esq at Somerville, NJ, First Floor Plan. Kendall, Taylor & Stevens, architects. [circa 1907]. Pencil and blue watercolor. (Oversize-folder C1D3F3)
    - Proposed Country House for J.B. Duke, Esq at Somerville, NJ, Second Floor Plan. Kendall, Taylor & Stevens, architects. [circa 1907]. Pencil and blue watercolor. (Oversize-folder C1D3F3)
    - Proposed Country House for J.B. Duke, Esq at Somerville, NJ, Second Floor Plan. Kendall, Taylor & Stevens, architects. [circa 1907]. Pencil and auburn watercolor. (Oversize-folder C1D3F3)
    - Proposed Country House for J.B. Duke, Esq at Somerville, NJ, Preliminary Plan for the Terrace Aviary. Innocenti & Webel. 1938 Dec. Positive photostat. (Oversize-folder C1D3F3)
    - Proposed Country House for J.B. Duke, Esq at Somerville, NJ, Plan of 1st Story - A. Kendall Taylor & Stevens, architects. 1907 Jun 15. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D3F3)
    - Proposed Country House for J.B. Duke, Esq at Somerville, NJ, Plan of 1st Story Scheme "B" - A. Kendall Taylor & Stevens, architects. 1907 Jun 15. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D3F3)
    - Proposed Country House for J.B. Duke, Esq at Somerville, NJ, Plan of 2nd Story - A. Kendall Taylor & Stevens, architects. 1907 Jun 15. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D3F3)
    - Proposed Country House for J.B. Duke, Esq at Somerville, NJ, First Floor Plan - B. Kendall Taylor & Stevens, architects. 1907 Jun 15. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D3F3)
    - Proposed Country House for J.B. Duke, Esq at Somerville, NJ, Second Floor Plan - B. Kendall Taylor & Stevens, architects. 1907 Jun 15. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D3F3)
    - Proposed Country House for J.B. Duke, Esq at Somerville, NJ, Plan of 1st Story - C. Kendall Taylor & Stevens, architects. 1907 Jun 15. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D3F3)
    - Proposed Country House for J.B. Duke, Esq at Somerville, NJ, Plan of 2nd Story - C. Kendall Taylor & Stevens, architects. 1907 Jun 15. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D3F3)
    - Proposed Country House for J.B. Duke, Esq at Somerville, NJ, First Story Plan - D. Kendall Taylor & Stevens, architects. 1907 Jun 15. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D3F3)
    - Proposed Country House for J.B. Duke, Esq at Somerville, NJ, Second Story Plan - D. Kendall Taylor & Stevens, architects. 1907 Jun 15. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D3F3)
    - Proposed Country House for J.B. Duke, Esq at Somerville, NJ, [First Floor Plan] - E. Kendall Taylor & Stevens, architects. 1907 Jun 15. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D3F3)
    - Proposed Country House for J.B. Duke, Esq at Somerville, NJ, Second Floor Plan - E. Kendall Taylor & Stevens, architects. 1907 Jun 15. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D3F3)
    - Country House for Mr. J.B. Duke, Plan Showing Piles for Terraces, Pools, Etc. Horace Trumbauer, architect. 1909 Sep 14; revised 1910 Apr 6. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D3F4)
    - Country House for Mr. J.B. Duke, Pile Plan. Horace Trumbauer, architect. 1909 Sep 14; revised 1910 Apr 6. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D3F4)
    - Country House for Mr. J.B. Duke, Framing Plan, Basement Floor. Horace Trumbauer, architect. 1909 Sep 14. Drafting cloth blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D3F4)
    - Country House for Mr. J.B. Duke, Detail of Fountains, Cascades and Driveway on North Elevation. Horace Trumbauer, architect. 1910 Dec 19. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D3F4)
    - Country House for Mr. J.B. Duke, Plan of Fountain Curbs. Buckenham & Miller, landscape engineers. 1910 Dec 14. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D3F4)
    - Country House for Mr. J.B. Duke, Reinf. For Concrete Footings Under Walls of Terraces. Horace Trumbauer, architect. 1910 Oct 26. Bluenprint. (Oversize-folder C1D3F4)
    - Detail Showing Revised Grades at SE and SW Corners. Horace Trumbauer, architect. 1911 May 17. Blueprint, photocopy. (Oversize-folder C1D3F5)
    - Plan of Fountain Curbs. Horace Trumbauer, architect. 1911 Mar 24. Blueprint, photocopy. (Oversize-folder C1D3F5)
    - Details of Large Pool Adjoining Porte Cochere. Horace Trumbauer, architect. 1911 Mar. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D3F5)
    - Plan of Cement Fountain & Curb. [Buckenham & Miller]. undated. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D3F5)
    - Detail of Coping to Four Corner Pools in Corners of Terrace. Horace Trumbauer, architect. 1910 Dec 13. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D3F5)
    - Revised Detail of Coping to Four Corner Pools in Corners of Terrace. Horace Trumbauer, architect. 1910 Dec 13. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D3F5)
    - Detail of Main Entrance. Horace Trumbauer, architect. [1909]. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D3F5)
    - Country House for Mr. J.B. Duke, Sub Basement Plan Showing Relative Position of Proposed New Building to Existing Foundations. Horace Trumbauer, architect. 1916 Jun 22. Ink on drafting cloth. (Oversize-folder C1D3F6)
    - Country House for Mr. J.B. Duke, Second Floor Plan. Horace Trumbauer, architect. undated. Ink. (Oversize-folder C1D3F6)
    - Country House for Mr. J.B. Duke, Basement Floor Plan. Horace Trumbauer, architect. undated. Photostat. (Oversize-folder C1D3F6)
    - Country House for Mr. J.B. Duke, Third Floor Plan. Horace Trumbauer, architect. undated. Ink. (Oversize-folder C1D3F6)
    - Country House for Mr. J.B. Duke, Sketch No. 2. undated. Ink on drafting cloth. (Oversize-folder C1D3F6)
    - Plan Showing Outer Terraces. Sheet No. 44. Horace Trumbauer, architect. 1910 Nov 16. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D3F7)
    - Detail of Outer Terrace. Horace Trumbauer, architect. 1910 Nov 9. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D3F7)
    - Country House for Mr. J.B. Duke, Basement Plan, Sheet No. 19. Horace Trumbauer, architect. [1910 Mar]. Blueprint. (Tube TU101)
    - Country House for Mr. J.B. Duke, [First Floor Plan], Sheet No. 20. Horace Trumbauer, architect. 1910 Mar 2. Blueprint. (Tube TU101)
    - Country House for Mr. J.B. Duke, Second Floor Plan. Horace Trumbauer, architect/W.T.K. 1910 Mar 4. Blueprint. (Tube TU101)
    - Country House for Mr. J.B. Duke, Third Floor Plan. Horace Trumbauer, architect/W.T.K. 1910 Mar 21. Blueprint. (Tube TU101)
    - Country House for Mr. J.B. Duke, South Elevation. Horace Trumbauer, architect. [1910 Mar]. Blueprint. (Tube TU101)
    - Country House for Mr. J.B. Duke, North Elevation. Horace Trumbauer, architect. [1910 Mar]. Blueprint. (Tube TU101)
    - Country House for Mr. J.B. Duke, East Elevation. Horace Trumbauer, architect. [1910 Mar]. Blueprint. (Tube TU101)
    - Country House for Mr. J.B. Duke, [East and West Side Cross Sections]. Horace Trumbauer, architect. [1910 Mar]. Blueprint. (Tube TU101)
    - Country House for Mr. J.B. Duke, One-Half Plan and Elevations. Horace Trumbauer, architect. undated. Blueprint. (Tube TU101)
    - Dukes Park: Mansion [Landscape Plan], Plan 1015.3. Buckenham & Miller, landscape engineers. 1912 Mar 11. Linen. (Tube TU200)
    - Mansion Plantings. [circa 1910-1912]. Photocopy. (Tube TU200)
    - Detail of Outer Terrace. Horace Trumbauer, architect. 1910 Nov 5. Blueprint. (Tube TU200)
    - Detail of Terrace Walls and Coping for Pools. Horace Trumbauer, architect. 1910 Nov 30. Blueprint. (Tube TU200)
    - [Grading Plan]. 1910 Jan 24. Paper mounted on vellum. (Tube TU304)
  - Duke Farms Pump & Filter House Systems, 1897-1915, 1934, 1938, 1965-1967 and undated
    - [Pump House Filtration System]. Fauss, James Vincent; Ray Palmer Assoc. Inc./ H.P. 1967 Dec 16. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D5F1)
    - [Pump House Filtration System]. Ray Palmer Assoc. Inc. [1967 Dec 15]. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D5F1)
    - [Pump House Filtration System]. Ray Palmer Assoc. Inc./ H.P. 1967 Dec 13. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D5F1)
    - [Pump House Filtration System]. Ray Palmer Assoc. Inc./ H.P. 1967 Dec 13. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D5F1)
    - [Pump House Filtration System]. Ray Palmer Assoc. Inc./ H.P. 1967 Dec 15. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D5F1)
    - [Water (Filter House) System]. Ray Palmer Assoc. Inc./ J.F. [1967 Dec 15]. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D5F1)
    - Coagulent Pump. American Water Softener Company/A.W.B. 1908 Nov 14. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D5F2)
    - [Pump House Plans and Sections]. American Water Softener Company/J.E. 1909 Mar 22. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D5F2)
    - Arrangement of 6 Cyl. 10-3/4" x 14-1/2" Vertical Oil Engine. American Water Softener Company/A.W.B. 1909 May 12 Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D5F2)
    - Chemical Feed Device. American Water Softener Company/AWB. 1909 May 12. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D5F2)
    - Horizontal New York Sect. Wash Filter 8'-0" Dia. x 20'-0" Long, Details of General Construction. The New York Continental Jewell Filtration Co. 1906 Jun 15. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D5F2)
    - Cross Section of Filter Plant. American Water Softener Company/J.E. 1909 Apr 10. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D5F2)
    - Longitudinal Section of Filter Plant. American Water Softener Company/J.E. 1909 Apr 10. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D5F2)
    - Plan of Filter Plant. American Water Softener Company/J.E. 1909 Apr 12. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D5F2)
    - Steel Supports for the Duke Farm Filter Plant. American Water Softener Company/J.E. 1909 Apr 12. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D5F2)
    - 8'-0" Dia. x 25'-0" Long Pressure Filter, Air Wash. Belmont Iron Works/ J.G.S. 1909 May 26. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D5F2)
    - 8'-0" x 20'-0" Horizontal Steel Pressure Filter with Cast Iron Laterials. American Water Softener Company/ J.E. 1910 Jun 11. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D5F2)
    - Proposed Design of Pumping and Filter House. Belmont Iron Works/ M.H.H. 1909 May 26. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D5F2)
    - Anchor Bolt Plan, Pump & Filter House. NY Continental Jewell Filtration Co. 1906 Jun 28. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D5F2)
    - Elevation of Filter House. [Richards & Gaston]. [circa 1907]. Pencil. (Oversize-folder C1D5F3)
    - East Front. [Richards & Gaston]. [circa 1907]. Pencil. (Oversize-folder C1D5F3)
    - South Front. [Richards & Gaston]. [circa 1907]. Pencil. (Oversize-folder C1D5F3)
    - West Front. [Richards & Gaston]. [circa 1907]. Pencil. (Oversize-folder C1D5F3)
    - Pump and Filter House, Duke's Farms. Buckenham & Miller, landscape engineers. 1909 May. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D5F3)
    - Plan Showing Pipe Connection Bet. Pump and Filter. Buckenham & Miller, landscape engineers. 1909 Jul 17. Ink on drafting cloth. (Oversize-folder C1D5F3)
    - Plan of Suction Well and Pipes. Buckenham & Miller, landscape engineers. 1909 Jun 19. Ink on drafting cloth. (Oversize-folder C1D5F3)
    - Engine Room Plan. Buckenham & Miller, landscape engineers. 1909 Oct 27. Pen and pencil on drafting cloth. (Oversize-folder C1D5F3)
    - Typ. Section of One Half Power House. Buckenham & Miller, landscape engineers. [1909]. Ink on drafting cloth. (Oversize-folder C1D5F3)
    - James B. Duke Duke Farm Power House - Somerville, NJ - Switchboard Assembly. Westinghouse Electric & MFG Co./Nell. 1915 Nov 5. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D5F3)
    - Boiler Room. undated. Negative photostat. (Oversize-folder C1D5F3)
    - General Specifications. Gaston, L.P. 1897 May 7. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D5F6)
    - Front Elevation, Rear Elevation, Drawing No. 1. Gaston, L.P. 1897 May 7. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D5F6)
    - North Elevation, Drawing No. 2. Gaston, L.P. 1897 May 7. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D5F6)
    - South Elevation, Drawing No. 3. Gaston, L.P. 1897 May 7. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D5F6)
    - Longitudinal Section Thro Penstock, Cross Section, Drawing No. 4. Gaston, L.P. 1897 May 7. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D5F6)
    - Floor Plan, Drawing No. 5. Gaston, L.P. 1897 May 7. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D5F6)
    - Foundation Plan, Drawing No. 6. Gaston, L.P. 1897 May 7. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D5F6)
    - Specifications. [Gaston, L.P.] 1897 Jan 9. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D5F6)
    - 40' Samson Turbine Plant for The Raritan Water Power Co. Gaston, L.P.; James Leffel & Co. 1897 May 9. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D5F6)
    - [Estimate from Michael Hickey, Mason and Builder]. Michael Hickey. 1897 Jan 20. Ink. (Oversize-folder C1D5F6)
    - Somerset County Park Commission, New Jersey, Duke Island County Park - Filling of Raritan Water Power Canal - Coversheet & Location Plan. Goodkind & O'Dea, engineers. 1966 Jun. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D5F7)
    - Somerset County Park Commission, New Jersey, Duke Island County Park - Filling of Raritan Water Power Canal - Summary of Quantities (Sheet 2 of 17). Goodkind & O'Dea, engineers. 1966 Jun. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D5F7)
    - Somerset County Park Commission, New Jersey, Duke Island County Park - Filling of Raritan Water Power Canal - General Plan (Sheet 3 of 17). Goodkind & O'Dea, engineers. 1966 Jun. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D5F7)
    - Somerset County Park Commission, New Jersey, Duke Island County Park - Filling of Raritan Water Power Canal - Survey Base Line Ties (Sheet 4 of 17). Goodkind & O'Dea, engineers. 1966 Jun. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D5F7)
    - Somerset County Park Commission, New Jersey, Duke Island County Park - Filling of Raritan Water Power Canal - Canal Profile (Sheet 5 of 17). Goodkind & O'Dea, engineers. 1966 Jun. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D5F7)
    - Somerset County Park Commission, New Jersey, Duke Island County Park - Filling of Raritan Water Power Canal - Canal Cross Sections (Sheet 6 of 17). Goodkind & O'Dea, engineers. 1966 Jun. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D5F7)
    - Somerset County Park Commission, New Jersey, Duke Island County Park - Filling of Raritan Water Power Canal - Canal Cross Sections (Sheet 7 of 17). Goodkind & O'Dea, engineers. 1966 Jun. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D5F7)
    - Somerset County Park Commission, New Jersey, Duke Island County Park - Filling of Raritan Water Power Canal - Spillway & Gate (Sheet 8 of 17). Goodkind & O'Dea, engineers. 1966 Jun. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D5F7)
    - Somerset County Park Commission, New Jersey, Duke Island County Park - Filling of Raritan Water Power Canal - Concrete Structures (Sheet 9 of 17). Goodkind & O'Dea, engineers. 1966 Jun. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D5F7)
    - Somerset County Park Commission, New Jersey, Duke Island County Park - Filling of Raritan Water Power Canal - Duke Farms Pump House (Sheet 10 of 17). Goodkind & O'Dea, engineers. 1966 Jun. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D5F7)
    - Somerset County Park Commission, New Jersey, Duke Island County Park - Filling of Raritan Water Power Canal - Culvert Details (Sheet 11 of 17). Goodkind & O'Dea, engineers. 1966 Jun. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D5F7)
    - Somerset County Park Commission, New Jersey, Duke Island County Park - Filling of Raritan Water Power Canal - Miscellaneous Details (Sheet 12 of 17). Goodkind & O'Dea, engineers. 1966 Jun. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D5F7)
    - Somerset County Park Commission, New Jersey, Duke Island County Park - Filling of Raritan Water Power Canal - Miscellaneous Details (Sheet 13 of 17). Goodkind & O'Dea, engineers. 1966 Jun. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D5F7)
    - Somerset County Park Commission, New Jersey, Duke Island County Park - Filling of Raritan Water Power Canal - Details (Sheet 14 of 17). Goodkind & O'Dea, engineers. 1966 Jun. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D5F7)
    - Somerset County Park Commission, New Jersey, Duke Island County Park - Filling of Raritan Water Power Canal - Details (Sheet 15 of 17). Goodkind & O'Dea, engineers. 1966 Jun. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D5F7)
    - Somerset County Park Commission, New Jersey, Duke Island County Park - Filling of Raritan Water Power Canal - Details (Sheet 16 of 17). Goodkind & O'Dea, engineers. 1966 Jun. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D5F7)
    - Somerset County Park Commission, New Jersey, Duke Island County Park - Filling of Raritan Water Power Canal - Details (Sheet 17 of 17). Goodkind & O'Dea, engineers. 1966 Jun. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D5F7)
    - Somerset County Park Commission, Duke Island County Park - Raritan Water Power Canal - General Plan. Goodkind & O'Dea, engineers. 1967 Dec 6. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D5F7)
    - Somerset County Park Commission, Duke Island County Park - Raritan Water Power Canal - Concrete Structures. Goodkind & O'Dea, engineers. 1967 Dec 7. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D5F7)
    - Somerset County Park Commission, Duke Island County Park - Raritan Water Power Canal - Duke Farms Pump House. Goodkind & O'Dea, engineers. 1967 Dec 29. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D5F7)
    - Proposed Changes and Addition at Old Power House. I.J. Shaffer. [circa 1912]. Vellum. (Oversize-folder C1D5F8)
    - Pump House of Duke Farms. Sasaki, Tetsuo. 1967 Aug 17. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D5F9)
    - Piping of Filter House for Duke Farms. Sasaki, Tetsuo. 1967 Aug 17. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D5F9)
    - Somerset County Park Commission, Duke Island County Park - Reconstruction of Headgates and Gatehouse, Bridgewater Township, Somerset County. Goodkind & O'Dea, engineers. 1965 Jun. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D5F10)
    - Somerset County Park Commission, Duke Island County Park - Reconstruction of Head Gates - Abutment and Wall, Dwg No. 2 of 3. Goodkind & O'Dea, engineers. 1965 Jun. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D5F10)
    - Somerset County Park Commission, Duke Island County Park - Reconstruction of Head Gates - Gate House, Dwg No. 3 of 3. Goodkind & O'Dea, engineers. 1965 Jun. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D5F10)
    - Vertical Shaft Leffel Turbines, General Arrangement. James Leffel & Co./ V.C.H. 1938 Sep 14. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C3D2F3)
    - Pump and Filter House, Duke's Farms. Buckenham & Miller, landscape engineers. 1909 May. Ink on drafting cloth. (Tube TU 104)
  - Duke Farms Surveys, Roads, Fields, 1900-1937, 1951-1984 and undated
    - Map of the Doris Duke Estate, Hillsborough Township, N.J. Louis L. Miller. 1932. Positive photostat. (Oversize-folder C1D6F1)
    - Map of Lakes, Roads, Buildings & Water Mains, repairs Sept. 1965. Buckenham & Miller, landscape engineers. 1911 Jan. Photocopy. (Oversize-folder C1D6F2)
    - Map of Lakes, Roads, Buildings & Water Mains. Buckenham & Miller, landscape engineers. 1911 Jan. Photocopy. (Oversize-folder C1D6F2)
    - Map of Lakes, Roads, Buildings & Water Mains. Buckenham & Miller, landscape engineers. 1911 Jan. Diazo, photocopy. (Oversize-folder C1D6F2)
    - Doris Duke Estate. Decatur Farm Mgmt. Inc. 1958. Ink on drafting paper. (Oversize-folder C1D6F2)
    - Duke Farms, Drawn from Aerial Photo 1956. Includes Hydrant locations (1986), Water lines (1962-1966), and Field Drawing (1967). Donald H. Stires Associates. 1960. Diazo, photocopy. (Oversize-folder C1D6F3)
    - Duke Estate, Drawn from Aerial Photo 1960. Includes Planting Map (1960) and Planting Map (1961) Donald H. Stires Associates. 1960. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D6F3)
    - Doris Duke Estate. Donald H. Stires Associates. 1960 Jan 23. Diazo, positive blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D6F3)
    - Map of Lakes, Roads, Building & Water Mains on Estate of James B. Duke. Shows updated locations of valves and fire hydrants (undated). Buckenham & Miller. 1911 Jan. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D6F3)
    - Aerial Photography 1979, Sheet Number 42. Keystone Aerial Surveys Inc. 1979. Photograph on paper. (Oversize-folder C1D6F4)
    - Aerial Photography 1979, Sheet Number 43. Keystone Aerial Surveys Inc. 1979. Photograph on paper. (Oversize-folder C1D6F4)
    - Aerial Photography 1979, Sheet Number 57. Keystone Aerial Surveys Inc. 1979. Photograph on paper. (Oversize-folder C1D6F4)
    - Aerial Photography 1979, Sheet Number 58. Keystone Aerial Surveys Inc. 1979. Photograph on paper. (Oversize-folder C1D6F4)
    - Aerial Photograph. [1979]. Photograph on paper. (Oversize-folder C1D6F4)
    - Plan of Water Trough, Cross Section Thru Water Trough. Bliss Construction Company/[Donald Pantel]. 1951 Mar 3. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D7F1)
    - Site Plan of Proposed Individual Septic System for Four Dwellings. C. Meyn. 1963 Nov 1. Diazo with pen, diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D7F1)
    - Fountain Syst. Upgrade. C. Meyn. 1984 Jun. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D7F1)
    - Fountain Sytem Upgrade. C. Meyn. 1984 Jun. Pencil on film (Oversize-folder C1D7F1)
    - Temporary Seepage Pit to Serve the Dairy Barns at Duke Farms, Hillsborough Township, Somerset County, New Jersey.Richard H. Schindelar. 1965 Sep. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D7F1)
    - General Property Key Map of Dukes Parkway (County Route 16-S-1) Showing Existing Right of Way and Parcels to be Acquired, Sheet 1 of 3. Donald H. Stires Associates. 1967 Jun 6. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D7F1)